KHUONG QUYNH LONG

kql@huph.edu.vn Halveweg 43, 3600 Genk, Belgium Research profile: Research Gate Google Scholar Mobile: 0032 880 848 khuongquynhlong@gmail.com

I am a Medical doctor specializing in Preventive medicine. I have skills in clinical practice and research skills in Epidemiological research and Statistical analysis with 5-year experience in the application of analytics/statistics tools including R, Python, Stata, SAS, and MLwiN. My work aims to improve the health of vulnerable populations and to prevent the early development of NCDs. I have published more than 50 original articles in international peer-reviewed journals. I am a person who is always willing to learn and share, having a sense of responsibility, and pursuing a career in academia.

EDUCATION

Hasselt University Hasselt, Belgium 2021 - 2023 (expected)

Master of Statistics and Data Science - Biostatistics

VLIR-UOS ICP Scholarship - Belgian Government. Full scholarship (tuition, living stipend, health insurance, return airfare, visa application, and miscellaneous fees)

University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

2011 - 2017

Doctor of Medicine – Preventive Medicine

GPA: 7.53/10 (top 4/103 students) Graduation thesis: 10/10 (top 1)

WORKING EXPERIENCE

World Health Organization (WHO), Country Office for Vietnam Consultant (Part-time)

Research contract 04/2021 - 12/2021

Provide technical consultation for Universal Health Coverage team in monitoring health financial protection indicators (SDG 3.8.2) in Vietnam

- Instructed in a 5-day workshop in calculating and monitoring SDG 3.8.2 indicators for 35 stakeholders from WHO, Ministry of Health, General Statistics Office, Health Strategy and Policy Institute, and Hanoi University of Public Health
- Estimated the national trend of SDG 3.8.2 statistics in Vietnam from 1994 to 2020
- Wrote national report in SDG 3.8.2 monitoring and preparing manuscripts for publication

Hanoi University of Public Health, Vietnam

Hanoi, Vietnam

Researcher, Center for Population Health Science

12/2018 - 09/2021

Doing research on Public health issues and interventions with complex survey, longitudinal, and quasi-experimental design

- Designed, managed, and analyzed data for research projects
- Provided technical consultation for other teams in terms of study design and statistical analysis plan
- Lead the technical team of two national surveys: GSHS (conducted in 20 provinces) and GATS (conducted in 33 provinces)
- Wrote proposals for research grants and manuscripts for publication
- Wrote textbooks and taught in applied statistics and epidemiology for public health students, lecturers, and clinical doctors

International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI), Washington, D.C., United States Research assistant (Part-time)

Research contract 11/2019 - 06/2020

Project "A&T Maternal Nutrition Interventions, India." and "A&T Bangladesh Urban Maternal Nutrition"

- Conducted statistical analyses for the impact evaluation and cohort surveys
- Conducted literature reviews, statistical analysis and prepared manuscripts for publication

Family Health International; FHI 360 Vietnam

Research contract 03/2019 - 11/2019

Statistical consultant (Part-time)

Collaborated with IFPRI Research Fellows and Emory University in research of maternal and child health

- Analyzed data for a randomized control trial for the effects of preconception micronutrient supplementation on child development and intellectual functioning (7-year follow-up project)
- Analyzed large survey datasets included Demographic and Health Survey (DHS), National Family Health Survey (NFHS) of India and Bangladesh
- Provided support in the development of manuscripts for presentation and publication.

University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam 01/2018 - 11/2018

Researcher, HIV-Addiction Technology Transfer Center Conducted research in substance abuse treatment and HIV prevention

- Designed the study, managed and analyzed the data
- Implemented intervention programs for substance abuse treatment and HIV prevention

CV - Khuong Quynh Long | Page 1 of 2

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Hanoi University of Public Health

Statistical instructor

Hanoi, Vietnam 12/2018 – 09/2021

Collaborate with Epidemiology and Biostatistics departments, Hanoi University of Public Health in training research methodology and statistical analysis for lecturers, public health students, and clinical doctors

- "Basic course in health science research methodology and data analysis" (12 courses from 2018 to 2021, 1000+ attendees)
- "Longitudinal data analysis in epidemiological research" (Spring 2021, 60 attendees)
- "Applied Bayesian statistics in medical research with R and Stata" (Fall 2018, Fall 2019, 80 attendees)
- "Introduction to systematic review and meta-analysis" (Summer 2020, 40 attendees)
- "Introduction to Stata macro and reproducible tables with Stata" (Spring 2020, 120 attendees)
- "Data visualization with ggplot2" (Spring 2019, 40 attendees)
- "Applying Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs) in epidemiological research" (Spring and Winter 2018, 50 attendees)

University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam Teaching assistant, Faculty of Public Health

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam 09/2017 – 03/2018

- Prepared lectures and class activities focusing on Time series analysis on Environmental health studies
- Supervised two final-year Public health students in terms of their graduation thesis
- Lead a group of six undergraduate students in conducting systematic review and meta-analysis

SKILLS

Technical:

- Statistical analysis (R, Python, Stata, SAS, and MLwiN); Bayesian statistics (Stan, OpenBUGS, Greta)
- Causal inference (DAGitty)
- Product communication (R markdown and Shiny); Version control (Github, Gitlab)
- Others: Data visualization with Tableau, Photoshop, Netdraw, RDS Analyst

Personal: Interdisciplinary, organized, independent, innovative, optimistic, constructive

AWARDS

The annual merit-based scholarship for excellent students of University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City

2011 - 2017

Received 11 times of 12 semesters (10% students received this honor each semester; value each: 1-semester tuition fee)
Award of the best graduation thesis (the first thesis achieved a score of 10/10 in the faculty)
11/2017

PUBLICATIONS

Selected 5 articles

- Long QK, Ngoc-Anh H, Phuong HN, Hanh TT, et al. Clustering Lifestyle Risk Behaviors among Vietnamese Adolescents and Roles of School: A Bayesian Multilevel Analysis of Global School-Based Student Health Survey 2019. *The Lancet Regional Health Western Pacific*. 2021. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanwpc.2021.100225
- Long QK, Thinh OP, Thao TTK, Van Huy N, et al. Relationship between family functioning and health-related quality of life among methadone maintenance patients: a Bayesian approach. *Quality of Life Research*. 2020. doi: https://doi.org/10.1007/s11136-020-02598-z
- Long QK, Linh BP, Adler A, Shellaby JT, et al. Effect of community-based intervention on self-management of blood pressure among hypertensive adults: findings from the Communities for Healthy Hearts Quasi-experimental Study in Vietnam. *J Glob Health Sci.* 2020. doi: https://doi.org/10.35500/jghs.2020.2.e10
- Long QK, Hanh H, Hanh T, Quang L, et al. Treatment for COVID-19 patients in Vietnam: Analysis of time-to-recovery. *Asian Pac J Trop Med*. 2020;13(9):397-401. doi: https://doi.org/10.4103/1995-7645.289505
- Long QK, Vu T-VT, Huynh V-AN, Thai TT. Psychometric properties of the medical outcomes study: social support survey among methadone maintenance patients in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam: a validation study. Substance Abuse Treatment, Prevention, and Policy. 2018;13(1):8. doi: https://doi.org/10.1186/s13011-018-0147-4

Textbook: Chapter "Applied mixed-effects model for repeated measurement data" in textbook "Statistical analysis for experimental study in health science" Minh HV, et al. Medical publishing house. Hanoi, 2019. ISBN: 978-604-66-3626-7

Software: Long QK, Thinh OP, Minh HV. "Sample Size Calculator in Health Science Research". Copyright certified by the Copyright Office of Vietnam (Certificate No. 1804/2021/QTG).

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

Selected oral presentations

- Long QK, et al. HIV Prevalence and Factors Related to HIV Infection among Transgender Women in Vietnam: A Respondent Driven Sampling Approach. Presented at 12th International Women's and Children's Health and Gender (InWomen's) Group Conference, Virtual, June 19, 2020
- Long QK. Applied Bayesian Statistics in Medical Research: A Brief Introduction. Presented at International Conference on Applied Probability and Statistics (CAPS 2019), April 2019, Hanoi, Vietnam
- Long QK, et al. Factors associated with treatment dropout among methadone maintenance patients in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam: a multilevel survival analysis approach. Presented at Multilevel modelling workshop, May 2018, Hanoi, Vietnam